[Music]
use retention policies to avoid
unnecessary database
growth some tables in business Central
are intended for activity logging And
archiving it's a good idea to keep these
tables trimmed so you don't store
records forever this can be fully
automated with the use of retention
policies let's have a
look here you see the default retention
policies provided with business Central
it's up to you to enable the policies
you want
enforced in our company the job Q is
very active and produces a lot of
logging data data that has no value long
term let's set up a retention policy to
trim this
table set up a new policy we select the
table the job CU log entry we set the
retention period to 1 month but actually
now that I think about it I don't want
to store all data in this table for one
month it depends depends on if the job
queue has failed or successful so I I
deselect the apply to all records
setting let me Define the policies for
the subsets of this
table I want to keep failed job queue
log entries for 5 days I want to allow
people some reaction time so that they
can analyze these errors so let me set
up a retention period for 5 days for
this specific case but for the job Q
runs that are succeeded I don't want to
keep them more than just two days let me
see say success and set the retention
Period 2
days now I can enable this retention
policy and this will now continuously
make sure that data in the job key log
entry is deleted after two and 5 days
respectively with that it's super easy
to set up how data in these kinds of
tables should be governed and when it
should be deleted save your database
cost and do a good thing for performance
use for policies thank you for
[Music]
watching